<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Karthik&#39;s World</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Karthik&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>cogs in a machine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thoughts/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thoughts/education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It may come as a surprise to those who know me as the poster child of loving learning also despises the education system, but in the months since I&amp;rsquo;ve left high school, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but reflect on my work over the summer in a method of implication&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This summer, I was lucky to be connected to the Teachable AI Lab at Georgia Tech, and conducted an independent study over the course of two months analyzing a cognitive modeling algorithm. I worked with high intensity deliverables, was constantly humbled for my questions but thoroughly encouraged by my PhD advisor and Masters&amp;rsquo; coauthor, and conclusively, I learned more in those two months than I did through the majority of my senior year. It was that final realization that sparked a reflection on my interaction with the modern education system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>life is a solved game?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thoughts/predestination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thoughts/predestination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The title may hint that I argue in favor of predestination, but I&amp;rsquo;m prefacing this whole topic with the fact that I don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of predestination quite fundamentally and believe that debating its existence and value are two separate conversation topics. I will consider both here, but I intend for this blog to largely revolve around the second. Simply for the belief of devil&amp;rsquo;s advocacy, my goal is to reason with the concept as atheistically as possible and justify both existence and value under a framework of pure rationale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>introductions</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thoughts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thoughts/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every time I meet someone in our generation who’s absolutely locked in, they seem to have a generally strong and minimalist personal website, so I wanted to take a stab at it. I write a lot to get my thoughts out into general space and I figured it would be optimal for them to have some general place to live! This initial post should hopefully offer notes on the vibes of future posts and cover some more general information on the parts of this website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
