<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Karthik&#39;s World</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Karthik&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ai bubble go brr or nah</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thoughts/aibubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thoughts/aibubble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big question that everyone has been asking me is, &amp;ldquo;when will the AI bubble pop?&amp;rdquo; And indeed, our current economic climate seems to mimic signs of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started out this post with the goal to take a very argumentative stance on the fact that contrary to popular belief, the AI bubble would NOT pop, and that humanity would live on. As I laid out the evidence, however, I realized that the situation was more niche than&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>digital colonialism</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thoughts/modernai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thoughts/modernai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trigger Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; This report discusses trauma, mental illness, addiction, and eating disorders. There are mentions of suicide and self-harm and descriptions of graphic content, violence, explicit sexual situations, child sexual abuse, ethnic cleansing, and animal cruelty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am fully outraged at what I&amp;rsquo;ve just read. This is a short commentary more than it is a blog post (I promise the capitalism one is on the way) but I write this to emphasize how much it disgusts me that this is the current state of our intellectual movement. I hope that this spurs action from all of us in some way regardless of whether we&amp;rsquo;re involved with the industry or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>progress for progress&#39;s sake</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/unready/anticapitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/unready/anticapitalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is quite unorthodox for me, as I always try to keep my political beliefs out of social discussion, and I will be avoiding referencing real countries and governments so as to preserve the sanctity of the argument without bias. However, this work is extremely necessary, especially in light of some recent events regarding political activism and funding, not just in the USA, but across the world. This is a broader commentary on where power should come from, where priorities should lie, and what to take as &amp;ldquo;valuable&amp;rdquo; to iterate on humanity&amp;rsquo;s best whilst learning to let go of what holds us back. I&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing things in terms of resource allocation, so a more economical perspective, but know that my views can be easily transferred to a political dimension by referencing the value and distribution of responsibilities rather than resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>proof of life</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thoughts/proofoflife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thoughts/proofoflife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m breaking my rules from post #1, and yes, this will be a highly personal, highly introspective story with some hopeful generalizations about my broader motivations in life, in the hopes that I can both find people to connect to and a broader meaning to the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was writing another blog post on capitalism (which is nearing its completion - it&amp;rsquo;s my longest post yet but has a lot of formalizations to go) and I wanted to convey something that means a lot to me in recent times and what I have been reflecting on as far as what it means with regards to the rest of my life. It&amp;rsquo;s about success, the most rewarding part of my high school journey, and why I am currently frightened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cogs in a machine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thoughts/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thoughts/education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It may come as a surprise to those who know me as the poster child of loving learning also despises the education system, but in the months since I&amp;rsquo;ve left high school, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but reflect on my journey in a nonpositive way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This summer, I was lucky to be connected to the Teachable AI Lab at Georgia Tech, and conducted an independent study over the course of two months analyzing a cognitive modeling algorithm. I worked with high intensity deliverables, was constantly humbled for my questions but thoroughly encouraged by my PhD advisor and Masters&amp;rsquo; coauthor, and conclusively, I learned more in those two months than I did through the majority of my senior year. It was that final realization that sparked a reflection on my interaction with the modern education system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>life is a solved game?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thoughts/predestination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thoughts/predestination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The title may hint that I argue in favor of predestination, but I&amp;rsquo;m prefacing this whole topic with the fact that I don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of predestination quite fundamentally and believe that debating its existence and value are two separate conversation topics. I will consider both here, but I intend for this blog to largely revolve around the second. Simply for the belief of devil&amp;rsquo;s advocacy, my goal is to reason with the concept as atheistically as possible and justify both existence and value under a framework of pure rationale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>introductions</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/thoughts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/thoughts/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every time I meet someone in our generation who’s absolutely locked in, they seem to have a generally strong and minimalist personal website, so I wanted to take a stab at it. I write a lot to get my thoughts out into general space and I figured it would be optimal for them to have some general place to live! This initial post should hopefully offer notes on the vibes of future posts and cover some more general information on the parts of this website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;&#xA;.terminal-hover {&#xA;  position: relative;&#xA;  color: #d07fd6;&#xA;  text-decoration: none;&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.terminal-hover::after {&#xA;  content: &#34;&#34;;&#xA;  position: absolute;&#xA;  left: 0;&#xA;  bottom: 0;&#xA;  width: 0;&#xA;  height: 2px;&#xA;  background-color: #d07fd6;&#xA;  transition: width 0.3s ease;&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.terminal-hover:hover::after {&#xA;  width: 100%;&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.terminal-popup {&#xA;  visibility: hidden;&#xA;  opacity: 0;&#xA;  width: 350px;&#xA;  background: black;&#xA;  color: #d07fd6;&#xA;  border: 1px solid #d07fd6;&#xA;  border-radius: 6px;&#xA;  padding: 10px;&#xA;  position: absolute;&#xA;  z-index: 100;&#xA;  bottom: 120%;&#xA;  left: 50%;&#xA;  transform: translateX(-50%);&#xA;  transition: opacity 0.3s;&#xA;  font-size: 16px;&#xA;  line-height: 1.4;&#xA;  box-shadow: 0 0 10px #d07fd6;&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.terminal-hover:hover .terminal-popup {&#xA;  visibility: visible;&#xA;  opacity: 1;&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;/* Responsive layout for mobile */&#xA;.flex-section {&#xA;  display: flex;&#xA;  align-items: center;&#xA;  gap: 20px;&#xA;  margin-bottom: 30px;&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;@media (max-width: 768px) {&#xA;  .flex-section {&#xA;    flex-direction: column;&#xA;    text-align: center;&#xA;  }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;flex-section&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;flex: 3; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/georgiatech.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;georgia tech&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;flex: 4;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h2&gt;me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&#xA;      Hi! I’m &lt;span class=&#34;terminal-hover&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Karthik Singaravadivelan&lt;span class=&#34;terminal-popup&#34;&gt;&#xA;        me!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/karthik.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;london&#34; style=&#34;margin: auto; max-width: 90%; height: auto;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, a Computer Science + Psychology Major and Stamps President’s Scholar at Georgia Institute of Technology studying the intersection of &lt;span class=&#34;terminal-hover&#34;&gt;&#xA;  cognitive science&lt;span class=&#34;terminal-popup&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;strong&gt;Cognitive Science:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        The study of thought, learning, and mental organization, which draws on aspects of psychology, linguistics, philosophy, and computer modeling.&#xA;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;with modern applications of &lt;span class=&#34;terminal-hover&#34;&gt;&#xA;  artificial intelligence&lt;span class=&#34;terminal-popup&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;        The theory and development of computer systems able to perform tasks that normally require human intelligence, such as visual perception, speech recognition, decision-making, and translation between languages.&#xA;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Specifically, I’m interested in how we can recreate human-like performance by iterating on principles of human-like learning.&#xA;    &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>contact me</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/contactme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/contactme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The true measure of scientific progress is not just the ability to ask questions, but the ability to ask better questions. &lt;em&gt;— J. Robert Oppenheimer, American theoretical physicist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our world is best improved through mutual discovery and curiosity, and I live for the unexpected conversations that spark both confusion and clarity. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to have a conversation, work together, or entertain the wildest of possibilities with me, reach out!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>definitions</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/unready/definitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/unready/definitions/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>interests</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Somewhere, something incredible is waiting to be known. &lt;em&gt;— Carl Sagan, American astronomer and planetary scientist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If any of these ideas sound interesting, &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/contactme/&#34;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt;! These are all important interests to me, for which I have countless theories that have some but not all formalization and a generally comprehensive intuition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; align-items: flex-start; gap: 2rem; flex-wrap: wrap;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;!-- Lists on the left --&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;flex: 1; min-width: 250px;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h2&gt;Content Interests&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;World models&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Latent space analysis&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Cognitive architectures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Symbolic systems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Consciousness&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Fast physical simulations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h2&gt;Recreational Interests&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;    &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;The Big Why&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Predestination&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Astrophysics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Markovian dynamics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Faith&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Languages and thought&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Information theory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Spiderweb cognition&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;li&gt;Japan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;  &lt;!-- Image on the right --&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;flex: 1; min-width: 200px; display: flex; justify-content: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/fortmountain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Mountain State Park&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;picture taken in fort mountain state park&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>projects</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The work is its own reward. &lt;em&gt;— Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, British writer and physician&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;ongoing-efforts&#34;&gt;ongoing efforts&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-cobweb-for-psychological-chunking--isle--github&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[2025-06-11 - present]&lt;/em&gt; Cobweb for psychological &amp;ldquo;Chunking&amp;rdquo; @ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.isle.org/&#34;&gt;ISLE&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/karthiksing05/Chunking-Cobweb&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cobweb is a symbolic algorithm that aggregates instances into &amp;ldquo;concepts&amp;rdquo; and forms a hierarchy over these instances - it is unsupervised, piecemeal, and incremental, making it a comprehensive model for human learning. I am currently working with Dr. Pat Langley to implement the Cobweb algorithm in a proposed theoretical framework to model psychological &amp;ldquo;chunking&amp;rdquo; for efficient parsing, storage and retrieval of concepts based on a set of defined relations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If successful, this project holds large implications for the world of embeddings, able to generate a stable and continuously evolving latent space over a stream of data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-neurosymbolic-approaches-for-retrieval-augmented-generation--tail--github&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[2025-06-01 - present]&lt;/em&gt; Neurosymbolic Approaches for Retrieval-Augmented Generation @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://tail.cc.gatech.edu/&#34;&gt;TAIL&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Teachable-AI-Lab/RAG-Cobweb&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(see notes on Cobweb in my work with &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/projects/#---cobweb-for-psychological-chunking--isle--github&#34;&gt;ISLE&lt;/a&gt;) I am currently leading an independent study under Dr. Chris Maclellan in creating a robust, industry-sustainable neurosymbolic solution to retrieval-augmented generation, using Cobweb as the primary algorithm. After conducting studies, we submitted a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cogsys.org/proceedings/2025/paper-2025-8.pdf&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; on a preliminary study which not only qualified the efficacy of Cobweb as a search algorithm, but led to the innovation of a new metric that matches inner-product similarities for embeddings&amp;rsquo; semantic comparison and outperforms inner-product similarities in some case studies..&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My goal is to grow this project as a vehicle for justifying the tangible applicability of neurosymbolic systems. I also strive to analyze differentiable forms of symbolic systems like Cobweb with the goal to remove some of symbolic systems&amp;rsquo; most fundamental timesinks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-encoding-model-development--lit-lab&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[2025-08-27 - present]&lt;/em&gt; Encoding Model development @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.language-intelligence-thought.net/&#34;&gt;LIT Lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recently, I joined Professor Anya Ivanova and began contributing to the development of encoding models, models that can convert latent content that represents stimuli into direct voxel representations of brain states, measured by fMRI data. This project places large emphasis on model interpretability, with the goal of running large studies with brain simulations inspired by encoding models if they become successful.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Currently, I am investigating alternative architectures to the traditional encoding model architecture, and attempting to apply different definitions towards interpretability behind pure sparsity in an effort to produce better fits.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;past-projects&#34;&gt;past projects&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-simplyphi--wisc--github&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[2025-01-17 - 2025-04-17]&lt;/em&gt; SimplyPhi @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://sleep-and-consciousness.wisc.edu/&#34;&gt;WISC&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/karthiksing05/SimplyPhi&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I did volunteer work for Dr. Larissa Albantakis on a theory called Integrated Information Theory, an information-theoretic framework that attempted to calculate the distributed &amp;ldquo;consciousness&amp;rdquo; of the theory. I used IIT to evaluate the performance of neural networks as a saliency test, identifying the most relevant parts of the network under the &amp;ldquo;substrate of consciousness&amp;rdquo; defined by the framework.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While IIT is an extremely assuming framework to attribute to consciousness, as a metric of &amp;ldquo;usefulness&amp;rdquo; by analyzing the distributed information across a system, it has a lot of play, and I look forward to seeing information theory take greater prominence in shaping the field of ML interpretability.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-duluthgpt--duluth-high-school--github&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[2023-08-27 - 2025-05-25]&lt;/em&gt; DuluthGPT @ Duluth High School | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/karthiksing05/duluthgptv2&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At my high school, our student body&amp;rsquo;s ratio of participation to population was disproportionately small, and through my work with student leadership, I discerned part of the gap to be due to a decentralized bank of resources - conflicting information and not a single place to easily access everything. So, I created DuluthGPT, an LLM agent that scraped and added data from athletics websites, extracurricular Instagrams, and the student body themselves, and was able to quickly answer fast Q+A with a basic RAG pipeline.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In addition to answering over 3,000 queries and increasing student engagement by 10%, we were able to analyze results by measuring the frequency of topics asked about, highlighting AI&amp;rsquo;s useful two-way value proposition in consumer interaction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-ai-for-advertising--ga-ghp---github&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[2024-06-18 - 2024-07-16]&lt;/em&gt; AI-for-Advertising @ &lt;a href=&#34;https://gosa.georgia.gov/governors-honors-program&#34;&gt;GA GHP &amp;lsquo;61&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/karthiksing05/sd3dblora_finetune&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I attended the Georgia Governor&amp;rsquo;s Honors Program for Computer Science in my junior year, where I had the pleasure of launching a mock-startup and conducting research under my advisor. Over the term, I wrote a piece on the application of finetuning diffusion models for the advertising industry based on user demographic and , with the broader social commentary of introducing profitable AI research into the research space before industry so that it could be appropriately regulated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My paper was accepted to the Applied Human Factors and Ergonomics Conference, but I was unfortunately unable to attend due to another commitment. Paper can be viewed &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Gn6mnmxkvGaBaOAdVu16wN3FsUyRCiVS/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-8ball--github&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[2020-08-27 - present]&lt;/em&gt; 8ball | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/karthiksing05/8ball&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My first full-production machine learning pipeline was applied to the stock market. I used an XGBoost pipeline, tuned with my &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/projects/#---biaswrappers--github&#34;&gt;Biaswrappers&lt;/a&gt;, and finetuned predictions using sentiment analysis on Reddit, X, Google News, and Yahoo Finance investor analysis. My goal was to use the momentum of prior stock movements and current news sentiment to analyze the trends of future stock predictions by OHLC, and my framework, though generally performing worse or equal to day-to-day predictions, had some highly successful calls with returns of up to 30%-40% for stocks that weren&amp;rsquo;t mainstream.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-biaswrappers--github&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;[2021-09-27 - 2024-02-05]&lt;/em&gt; BiasWrappers | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/karthiksing05/biaswrappers&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My first machine learning project and independently published paper to a preprint archive! A brief foray into classical forms of regularization on linear regression, including two of my own attempts at unsupervised regularization with respect to the data distribution. The python package currently stands at ~32k downloads!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paper can be viewed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techrxiv.org/users/741672/articles/713955-on-biaswrappers-new-regularization-techniques-for-machine-learning-regression&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, Python Package can be viewed &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/biaswrappers/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>quotebook</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/quotebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/quotebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Life itself is a quotation. — Jorge Luis Borges, Argentine short story writer and essayist&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;purpose&#34;&gt;purpose&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Live as if you were to die tomorrow. Learn as if you were to live forever. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Mahatma Gandhi, Indian lawyer and activist]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The world offers you comfort. But you were not made for comfort. You were made for greatness. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Pope Benedict XVI, Former head of the Catholic Church]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The meaning of life is to find your gift. The purpose of life is to give it away. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Pablo Picasso, Spanish painter]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He who has a why to live can bear almost any how. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Friedrich Nietzsche, German philosopher]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What man actually needs is not a tensionless state but rather the striving and struggling for some goal worthy of him. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Viktor Frankl, Austrian neurologist and psychiatrist]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I wrote a pep talk recently to myself on a bar napkin: &lt;em&gt;no matter which road you take, it will be both glorious and unbearable.&lt;/em&gt; Every road is lonely. Every road, holy. The only error is not walking forward. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Joy Sulivan, American poet and educator]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;curiosity&#34;&gt;curiosity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The most beautiful experience we can have is the mysterious. It is the fundamental emotion which stands at the cradle of true art and true science. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Albert Einstein, German theoretical physicist and realist]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nothing in life is to be feared; it is only to be understood. Now is the time to understand more, so that we may fear less. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Marie Curie, Polish-French physicist and chemist]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I know very little about acting. I just jump in, have fun, and see what happens. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Robert Downey Junior, American actor and philanthropist]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wonder is the beginning of wisdom. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Socrates, Greek philosopher]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stay hungry, stay foolish. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Steve Jobs, American entrepreneur]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;self&#34;&gt;self&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is not our abilities that show us what we truly are. It is our choices.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Albus Dumbledore, fictional character from &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I think, therefore I am. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[René Descartes, French philosopher and mathematician]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Knowing yourself is the beginning of all wisdom. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Aristotle, Greek philosopher]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The unexamined life is not worth living. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Socrates, Greek philosopher]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What lies behind us and what lies before us are tiny matters compared to what lies within us. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Ralph Waldo Emerson, American essayist and philosopher]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
